<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Scrooling Text</string>
    <string name="article_title"><b>Dark</b></string>
    <string name="article_subtitle">The question is not where, but when.</string>
    <string name="article_text" align="justify">"The distinction between past, present and future is
    only a stubbornly persistent illusion" ― Albert Einstein.
    Dark is a German science fiction thriller family drama series created by Baran bo Odar and
    Jantje Friese. Set in the fictional small town of Winden, it revolves around four interconnected
    families haunted by their secrets, and contains elements of science fiction and fantasy. The
    series is Netflix first original German series. The first season, comprising 10 episodes,
    premiered on December 1, 2017. The second season, comprising 8 episodes, was released on June
    21, 2019. The third and final season, comprising 8 episodes, premiered on June 27, 2020.
    \n\n
    <b><i>Premise</i></b>
    When two children go missing in a small German town, its sinful past is exposed along with the
    double lives and fractured relationships that exist among four families as they search for the
    kids. The mystery-drama series introduces an intricate puzzle filled with twists that includes
    a web of curious characters, all of whom have a connection to the town troubled history; whether
    they know it or not. The story includes supernatural elements that tie back to the same town in
    1986. "Dark" represents the first German original series produced for Netflix.
    \n\n
    <b><i>Conception</i></b>
    The series was created by Swiss director Baran bo Odar and German writer Jantje Friese. It was
    produced by Quirin Berg, Max Wiedemann and Justyna Müsch. All of the aforementioned had
    previously collaborated on the 2014 film Who Am I, which grossed $6 million at the local box
    office and won three German Movie Awards and the Bambi for “Best German Film.” Netflix
    approached Odar and Friese after seeing Who Am I at the Toronto Film Festival in 2014, asking
    if they could make a series out of it. Reluctant to repeat themselves, Odar and Friese instead
    pitched other ideas to Netflix, one of which was Dark. Dark was Netflix first original series
    entirely authored, shot and produced in Germany. The move into German television drama was part
    of the company global strategy, with which they hoped to attract more foreign subscribers and
    boost their library of originals worldwide. Odar and Friese felt that German television was
    associated with something ugly and sad, and that all German series were either thrillers or
    crimes, so they wanted to create something of a higher quality for a universal audience. They
    were inspired by the Scandinavian Nordic Noir genre.
    \n\n
    <b><i>Writing</i></b>
    Initially, Dark was an idea for a crime show they had written two years prior to being contacted
    by Netflix. They had another idea for a time travel feature film and they combined the two ideas.
    Having grown up in a small town themselves, the creators had a fascination with the subject of
    the darkness hiding behind closed doors in a small town. David Lynch Twin Peaks, which deals
    with the same topic, shaped them in their teenage years. They were also inspired by their
    childhoods in German small towns during the Chernobyl nuclear disaster, when release of
    radioactive materials spread fears of contamination. Other influences are Stephen King and
    David Lynch.There are 72 characters in the series, including three different actors for the same
    character across three different time periods. Friese called structuring it a "complex task."
    Before its release, the series was often compared to Stranger Things based on its premise and
    partial 1980s setting. However, Dark was already in pre-production when Stranger Things
    premiered and the series is much darker and not for kids. Friese stated they enjoyed the
    comparisons, saying: "It’s really exciting because if all those people who watched Stranger Things
    will at least think about watching Dark, I think that’s a great opportunity for us."
    Some details had to be changed for the international audience to understand it. For example,
    some instances of sarcasm in dialogue did not translate well to English because of the
    difference in tone. However, Netflix were okay with keeping some things which only Germans would
    understand, as long as the overall narrative worked for everyone. The series concluded after a
    third season, which the creators had envisioned from the beginning, with Bo Odar commenting they
    did not want to end up like Lost. For more informations https://dark-netflix.fandom.com/wiki/Dark
    </string>
</resources>